Guide to the Labor-Management Relations, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Labor-Management Relations, Yale University, records
1942-1996
RU 977
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.25
(8 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, and news clippings documenting contract negotiations between Yale and Local 34, Local 35, and the police union; union organizing drives; and labor strikes.
Yale University. Dept of Human Resources
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 5-G (YRG 5-G), Records documenting personnel services at Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Labor-Management Relations office, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is partially restricted. See collection contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, and news clippings documenting contract negotiations between Yale and Local 34, Local 35, and the police union; union organizing drives; and labor strikes.
Industrial relations; Labor disputes; Labor unions; Strikes and lockouts; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Labor unions; Federation of University Employees; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University. Dept of Human Resources
- Records relating to union negotiations at Yale, 1942-1996; Accession 2005-A-129
  General
  The News clippings and printed materials series is open for research. The Yale records series is closed until January 1, 2031 by order of the Office of the Secretary.
  - News clippings and print materials
    Conditions Governing Access
    The materials are open for research.
    - AFL-CIO report to Local 34, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Don Stevens article-1985 strike (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Joint letter to President Giamatti: minority student groups in support of striking employees, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Local 34 ephemera, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Local 34 event memorabilia, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Local 34 fact sheet: negotiation summary, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Local 34 "In Good Faith" newsletter, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Local 34: letters, calendars, notes and ephemera, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Local 34 memorabilia, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Local 34 news clippings
      - 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
      - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
    - Local 34 press releases, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Local 34 union organizing: election fact book and memorabilia, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Local 35 negotations: press clippings, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Local 35 news clippings and articles, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Local 35 news clippings
      - 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
      - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
    - National Labor Relations Board news clippings, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - Negotiations-news clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Negotiations-news clippings
      - 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
      - 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 10-13)
      - 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Strike articles, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Strike news clippings
      - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
      - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
      - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
      - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Strikes and union news clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Unionization news clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - United Automobile Workers: correspondence and ephemera, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Yale Non-Faculty Action Committee: news clippings, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)